Guide to the Roone Arledge Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: ABC News, 1977-2002
  - Program Development
    - Seven Days, 1996 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Turning Point, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Shows
    - 20/20, 1985-1990 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Good Morning America, 1996-1998 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Nightline, 1993-2002 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Sunday Morning Show, 1997-1998 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - World News Tonight, 1993-1997 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Trips
    - ABC Dinner, 1994-1997 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Affiliate Stations, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Berlin, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - China, 1979-1995 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Cuba, 1997 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Ireland, 1989-1996 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Jerusalem Conference, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Moscow, 1985-1998, (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 10 to 11)
  - Worldwide Television News, 1998-2002 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Washington D.C. Bureau, 1996-1998 (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Series IV: ABC Sports, 1961-2001
  This small series holds topical files in regards to ABC Sports. General administrative records, records pertaining to the NFL, Monday Night Football, Wide World of Sports, and the network coverage of the Goodwill Games, championship boxing, and Major League Baseball are found in this series. There is also documentation of the many Olympic Games that were covered including Calgary, Seoul, Los Angeles, and Sarajevo. The Olympic records illustrate the amount of synchronization and planning that Roone Arledge and his team were required to do in order to cover the multiple competitions occurring at the event. Additionally, there are transcripts of testimonies by Howard Cosell and Roone Arledge, correspondence, and accompanying documents concerning the Subcommittee on Communications' review of the Communications Act of 1934, particularly with regard to in particular how television networks (and, in this case, sports divisions) obtained programming
  - General Administrative Records, 1977-1986 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1986-1988 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Baseball, 1983-1989 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Boxing, 1977-1983 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Contract, 1966 September 1 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Cosell, Howard, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Goodwill Games, 1984-1988 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Hall of Fame Dinner, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Korea, 1982-1987 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - NFL
    - General, 1967-1971, (2 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Correspondence, 1980 February-1984 June (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Rozelle Meetings, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Olympics
    - General, 1976-1984 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Baden, 1981-1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Barcelona, 1984-1992 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Calgary, 1982-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Hall of Fame, 1982-1989 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Innsbruck, 1973-1976 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Olympic Moments, 1985-1987 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Sarajevo, 1980-1984 (Box 36, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Seoul, 1984-1985 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Skycam, 1983-1985 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Subcommittee Hearings, 1976-1978, (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 2 to 4)
  - United States Football League (USFL)--General, 1982-1986, (2 Folders) (Folder 5 to 6)
    - Court Transcripts, 1986 June 11 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - USFL--Court Transcripts, 1986 June 12 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Wide World of Sports, 1961-2001 (Box 38, Folder 2)
- Series V: Photographs, 1984-1994
  There are a small number of photographs within this collection. Most were taken while Arledge was receiving some type of recognition, such as his honorary degree from Boston University. There are also photographs from his visit to the White House and the meeting with executives from the Japan-based television network, Nippon Hoso Kyokai.
  - 1984-1986 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - 1991-1994 (Box 38, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Realia, undated, 1989-1992
  This series is composed of several objects such as commemorative stamps and an award given by the Wrestling Hall of Fame. Of particular interest are several sets of Russian nesting dolls acquired in one of Roone Arledge's many trips to Moscow. These matreshka" depict political leaders who have had an impact on Russia's cultural and political history. Examples include Mikhail Gorbachev and his cabinet members, Stalin, chief prosecutors (with the names of those that were killed during their time), and the successive heads of numerous secret police organizations leading up to the KGB.
  - Nobel Peace Prize Stamps, 1989 March 17 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Russian Nesting Dolls, 1980s (Box 39)
  - Wrestling Hall of Fame, 1992 (Box 40)